<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ThirstyMinds – Micro-Blog</title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Micro-Blog on ThirstyMinds</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	  <atom:link href="//localhost:1313/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
        
      
    
    
    <item>
      <title>How GNU/Linux make students better engineers?</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/blog/betterstudents/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//localhost:1313/blog/betterstudents/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;How a simple change of using linux as daily driver can change students perspective in engineering&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You won&amp;rsquo;t be scared of terminal and terminal tools. You don&amp;rsquo;t have dependencies with GUI tools/editors to engineer your product.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Increases your problem-solving skills when you tackle your system&amp;rsquo;s software installations and customizations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It breaks you out from the vendor lock-in software.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Let you make mistakes and more importantly fix those mistakes by yourself.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Since GNU/Linux don&amp;rsquo;t have a licensing/subscription cost, it is affordable for students without sacrificing the quality of software to work with.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Teaches you how software works, how it interacts with OS in a fundamental way without masking them with unnecessary wrappers like proprietary software does.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Let you compile your own software from code and gives you the necessary tools for the same for free.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fundamentals first approach, Keep It Short and Simple philosophy in your development and workflow.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Exposure to more Open Source tools via Linux helps you find projects driven by communities.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can even download the Linux kernel code and dissect it to learn more about kernels and operating systems.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Certain Linux distros teach you how to put together your system instead of defaulting to GUI.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Minimal resources needed for running Linux can help you to revive your old computers so students who are economically challenged can still get a few-years-old hardware and still be able to work on it with Linux.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The list goes on and on&amp;hellip; Just to keep it short and simple, I mentioned only major points.&lt;/p&gt;
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Foss ?</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/blog/why/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//localhost:1313/blog/why/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Reason why you should try foss and improve your flow&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Choosing foss over proprietary software is a conscious choice one has to take.&lt;br&gt;
But why you should consider one?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When proprietary software too gets your job done and saves your day. What else free and open source software can offer. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It helps us to do a lot of collaboration and collective effort of users drive the flow of the product rather than a MNC with zero regards to the end user preferences.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It gives you transparency which no amount of privacy policy can offer but only open source code alone can offer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It helps to customise the application / technology to our needs. So we don&amp;rsquo;t have to go through the discomfort of adapting and using one particular way or methods.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It makes you faster with updates. Since open source software is developed by contributors who is also the users of the same. New features and security updates are delivered faster than any MNC company&amp;rsquo;s release cycle.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It helps you learn about how things work, since the code is open you can read it, observe it, digest it on what it does and how it does. With help of forums you can discuss about the design and architecture with actual code contributors.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
