<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ThirstyMinds – Release</title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/tags/release/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Release on ThirstyMinds</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	  <atom:link href="//localhost:1313/tags/release/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
        
      
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Foss ?</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/blog/why/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//localhost:1313/blog/why/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Reason why you should try foss and improve your flow&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Choosing foss over proprietary software is a conscious choice one has to take.&lt;br&gt;
But why you should consider one?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When proprietary software too gets your job done and saves your day. What else free and open source software can offer. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It helps us to do a lot of collaboration and collective effort of users drive the flow of the product rather than a MNC with zero regards to the end user preferences.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It gives you transparency which no amount of privacy policy can offer but only open source code alone can offer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It helps to customise the application / technology to our needs. So we don&amp;rsquo;t have to go through the discomfort of adapting and using one particular way or methods.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It makes you faster with updates. Since open source software is developed by contributors who is also the users of the same. New features and security updates are delivered faster than any MNC company&amp;rsquo;s release cycle.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It helps you learn about how things work, since the code is open you can read it, observe it, digest it on what it does and how it does. With help of forums you can discuss about the design and architecture with actual code contributors.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
